Common tips =Windows 8.1 32 bit=
- Most if not all dive-computer drivers are unsigned, and Windows 8* won't install them unless booted in "disable driver signature enforcement" mode. See TODO:ref for how to do that. Driver/software installation may involve several reboots; any reboot made for the purpose of installing a _driver_ should be done in this mode. E.g. in many cases, though not always, if prompted to reboot during the process, choose "later" and reboot with driver signature enforcement off; the decision depends on what is going to be installed right now, driver or application software
- If installing on a tablet, ensure that:
-- Charger is available and power socket is accessible - install may require heavy downloads, and they could be too slow when on battery
-- You have wired USB keyboard and an adapter for it - needed to disable driver signature enforcement
- Create restore point before starting the process


Installing Suunto DM5
=Windows 8.1 32 bit=
- Reboot using the "disable driver signature enforcement" procedure
- Ensure internet is always connected, especially immediately after reboot
-- If using wireless internet, choose "connect automatically" option
- Start the setup - as administrator
- If the messages indicate downloading files from the internet, and the connection is wireless, temporarily plug the power adapter in - this can significantly speed-up the downloads
- If prompted to reboot in order to install .NET, MSVC redistributable or other non-driver software, do permit the immediate auto-reboot; otherwise the installation fails - looks like it wants to download before wireless connection reestablished after the reboot
- When the driver- and application-software installation finished, do not connect the adapter, but reboot again using the "disable driver signature enforcement" procedure
- After the reboot above, connect the Suunto adapter, and the installation will finish
- the manual doesn't tell how to physically plug the cable into D4i unit; you need to remove the rubber ring from the plug, then twist it into the socket

