Glossary
----------
- gray target - RAW image of a neutral-color object; preferably a white one
- ultimate photo (image) - RAW image of anything other than gray sample
- (RAW) converter - RAW editor
- Work directory - directory (folder) where input, output, and intermediate files for one dive are placed
TODO


White-balancing gray targets
-------------------------------------
The aim is to choose for each grey-target RAW WB settings that make its white/gray object appear neutral. Here we are dealing only with relations between color channels.
One should achieve this neutrality in custom-WB mode using only white-balance tools.

Preparation - relevant for all RAW editors:
- set sharpness to min
- set noise-reduction to max
- choose exposure compensation value that doesn't burn highlights on the target.
In most RAW editors you can apply the above settings to a group of RAWs, so do it for all gray targets.

RawTherapee
Note, RT installation may need a massage for your camera; see TODO:filename.
A bit tricky since RT adds red-blue slider to the standard set of color-temperature and tint. Moreover, click-WB algorithm, instead of  controlling this slider; uses it as input.
Thus in RT you need to set the value of red-blue slider prior to clicking on a neutral-color area.
Try to have minimal number of different red-blue slider values in  one dive. Typical value is 1.0 at shallow depth and 1.4 at 20...30 m. In most cases one can do with 2 or 3 values.

Still for some images clicking on a neutral area doesn't produce reasonable colors. If it happens, set the color by manually moving the sliders. Tip: give focus to a slider, move mouse pointer to the neutral area to see RGB values, control the slider with arrow keys. Use Tab key to switch to other sliders.
You can copy-paste your color settings to other similar images and use as a starting point. E.g. first paste the settings, then try to click-white-balance. If this "click" makes colors worse, undo it and adjust manually.

Corel Aftershot Pro
Here click-white-balance works nearly perfect. Still there are two issues to be aware of:
- Color-temperature and tint limits in the Aftershot GUI are somewhat narrow, and color corrections for medium and large depths easily go out of bounds. The color is computed correctly and stored in the settings file, so disregad values shown in the GUI.
- Default black-point value of 10% may cause red-channel value measured off the neutral surface to become zero. In this case click-white-balance fails. So set black-point to 0 before performing click-white-balance. This happened to me when shooting with FLD filter below 10m in blue water; FLB filter eliminated the problem.

PhotoNinja.
With respect to click-white-balance behavior visible to the user, PhotoNinja resembles AfterShot Pro. Here too all you need is to click a neutral area and the correction is set, though the typical color-temperature and tint values exceed limits in the GUI. The color-picker is too sensitive though, so one has to carefully choose the right spot. Looks like color-picker radius cannot be changed.

Todo












