Synchronizing clocks of cameras and dive-computers.
UWID relies on EXIF timestamp to correlate camera- and dive-computer data in order to estimate depth where a photo was taken. This implies that clocks of the two devices are in-sync.
Generally the task doesn't require more knowledge than what's present in user manuals, but some devices and device combinations could be tricky. So below are tips for some of such situations - those encountered by the author.

- Sony NEX C3 camera (a) freezes the clock when you enter time-setting mode, and (b) requests confirmation after the time adjustment is committed. The clock resumes only upon receiving that confirmation.
Press "set" two seconds before the right moment to allow some time for pressing another button (confirmation).

- Cressi Leonardo dive-computer has only a single button, thus making time adjustment a slow procedure.
As a workaround use the Leonardo as reference and set camera clock to match it.
Another problem with the Leonardo - it doesn't show seconds. Thus the only moment when the seconds' resolution is known is when minutes are switched. You can overcome it by using an additional clock with seconds display.

- A useful trick to synchronise Suunto D4i dive computer (and maybe others) with Sony NEX C3 camera: set the time you want on the camera, press OK, then press confirmation (on the camera) _simultaneously_ with the seconds-reset on the dive computer. You can freely adjust hours and minutes on the dive computer afterwards. The seconds are synchronized since NEX C3 starts time count upon obtaining the confirmation button press.
