I'm answering about stills photography without flash.
The filters should be used together with RAW white-balance correction. Filters reduce amount of the latter and thus improve the quality. If you find a way to postprocess white-balance in video, tell me how you do it.
Filter types:
- FLD for small depths - (0 - 15m) and green waters
- FLB for average and more depths - (10 - 30m) in blue waters

- maybe you need FLW for >20m in green waters; I didn't try.

Beware that FLB eats a lot of light. 

Example of green waters: Thailand - Koh-Pi-Pi.
Example of blue waters: Israel - Eilat.

Specialized UW filters are variations of the above. But if you cannot attach threaded filter, look at "Magic Filters" (gel).

